<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "+//IDN docutils.sourceforge.net//DTD Docutils Generic//EN//XML" "http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/docutils.dtd">
<!-- Generated by Docutils 0.16 -->
<document source="/research/anastasis/anastasis/contrib/pp/pp.rst">
    <section ids="privacy-policy" names="privacy\ policy">
        <title>Privacy Policy</title>
        <paragraph>Last Updated: 07.09.2021</paragraph>
        <paragraph>This Privacy Policy describes the policies and procedures of Anastasis
            SARL (“we,” “our,” or “us”) pertaining to the collection, use, and
            disclosure of your information on our sites and related mobile
            applications and products we offer (the “Services”). This Privacy
            Statement applies to your personal data when you use our Services, and
            does not apply to online websites or services that we do not own or
            control.</paragraph>
        <section ids="overview" names="overview">
            <title>Overview</title>
            <paragraph>Your privacy is important to us. We follow a few fundamental
                principles: We don’t ask you for personally identifiable information
                (defined below). That being said, your contact information, such as
                your phone number, social media handle, or email address (depending on
                how you contact us), may be collected when you communicate with us,
                for example to report a bug or other error related to Anastasis. We
                don’t share your information with third parties except when strictly
                required to deliver you our Services and products, or to comply with
                the law. If you have any questions or concerns about this policy,
                please reach out to us at <reference refuri="mailto:privacy@anastasis.lu">privacy@anastasis.lu</reference>.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="how-you-accept-this-policy" names="how\ you\ accept\ this\ policy">
            <title>How you accept this policy</title>
            <paragraph>By using our Services or visiting our sites, you agree to the use, disclosure,
                and procedures outlined in this Privacy Policy.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="what-personal-information-do-we-collect-from-our-users" names="what\ personal\ information\ do\ we\ collect\ from\ our\ users?">
            <title>What personal information do we collect from our users?</title>
            <paragraph>The information we collect from you falls into two categories: (i) personally
                identifiable information (i.e., data that could potentially identify you as an
                individual) (“Personal Information”), and (ii) non-personally identifiable
                information (i.e., information that cannot be used to identify who you are)
                (“Non-Personal Information”). This Privacy Policy covers both categories and
                will tell you how we might collect and use each type.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>We do our best to not collect any Personal Information from Anastasis
                users.  The detailed Personal Information Anastasis asks from you during
                the regular backup and recovery process at the beginning is never shared
                with us and only used to create a cryptographic account identifier which
                does not allow us to recover any of your details.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>That being said, when using our Services to recover key material, we may
                inherently receive the following information (depending on your choice of
                authentication method):</paragraph>
            <block_quote>
                <bullet_list bullet="*">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Bank account details necessary when receiving funds from you to authenticate via a SEPA transfer. We will store these as part of our business records for accounting, and our bank will also be legally obliged to store the details for many years.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Your phone number when using SMS authentication. We rely on third party providers (such as your mobile network operator) to deliver the SMS to you. These third parties will see the SMS message sent to you and could thus learn that you are using Anastasis. SMS is inherently insecure, and you should expect many governments and private parties to be able to observe these messages.  However, we do not store your SMS number on our systems, except maybe in short-term logs to diagnose errors.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Your e-mail address when using E-mail authentication. We rely on the Internet and your E-mail provider to deliver the E-mail to you. Internet service providers will see the E-mail message sent to you and could thus learn that you are using Anastasis. E-mail is inherently insecure, and you should expect many governments and private parties to be able to observe these messages.  However, we do not store your E-mail address on our systems, except maybe in short-term logs to diagnose errors.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>Your physical address when using postal mail authentication. We rely on external providers for printing and sending the letter to you. These providers will need to learn your address and could learn that you are using Anastasis. Physical mail has strict privacy protections by law, but governments are known to break postal secrecy. We do not store your physical address on our systems, except maybe in short-term logs to diagnose errors.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>When you contact us. We may collect certain information if you choose to contact us, for example to report a bug or other error with the Taler Wallet. This may include contact information such as your name, email address or phone number depending on the method you choose to contact us.</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
            </block_quote>
        </section>
        <section ids="how-we-collect-and-process-information" names="how\ we\ collect\ and\ process\ information">
            <title>How we collect and process information</title>
            <paragraph>We may process your information for the following reasons:</paragraph>
            <block_quote>
                <bullet_list bullet="*">
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>to authenticate you during secret recovery</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                    <list_item>
                        <paragraph>to support you using Anastasis when you contact us</paragraph>
                    </list_item>
                </bullet_list>
            </block_quote>
        </section>
        <section ids="how-we-share-and-use-the-information-we-gather" names="how\ we\ share\ and\ use\ the\ information\ we\ gather">
            <title>How we share and use the information we gather</title>
            <paragraph>We may share your authentication data with other providers that assist
                us in performing the authentication. We will try to use providers that
                to the best of our knowledge respect your privacy and have good
                privacy practices.  We reserve the right to change authentication
                providers at any time to ensure availability of our services.</paragraph>
            <paragraph>We primarily use the limited information we receive directly from you to
                enhance Anastasis. Some ways we may use your Personal Information are
                to: Contact you when necessary to respond to your comments, answer your
                questions, or obtain additional information on issues related to bugs or
                errors with the Anastasis application that you reported.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="agents-or-third-party-partners" names="agents\ or\ third\ party\ partners">
            <title>Agents or third party partners</title>
            <paragraph>We may provide your Personal Information to our employees, contractors,
                agents, service providers, and designees (“Agents”) to enable them to perform
                certain services for us exclusively, including: improvement and maintenance of
                our software and Services. By accepting this Privacy Policy, as outlined
                above, you consent to any such transfer.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="protection-of-us-and-others" names="protection\ of\ us\ and\ others">
            <title>Protection of us and others</title>
            <paragraph>We reserve the right to access, read, preserve, and disclose any information
                that we reasonably believe is necessary to comply with the law or a court
                order.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="what-personal-information-can-i-access-or-change" names="what\ personal\ information\ can\ i\ access\ or\ change?">
            <title>What personal information can I access or change?</title>
            <paragraph>You can request access to the information we have collected from
                you. You can do this by contacting us at <reference refuri="mailto:privacy@anastasis.lu">privacy@anastasis.lu</reference>. We will
                make sure to provide you with a copy of the data we process about
                you. To comply with your request, we may ask you to verify your
                identity. We will fulfill your request by sending your copy
                electronically. For any subsequent access request, we may charge you
                with an administrative fee. If you believe that the information we
                have collected is incorrect, you are welcome to contact us so we can
                update it and keep your data accurate. Any data that is no longer
                needed for purposes specified in the “How We Use the Information We
                Gather” section will be deleted after ninety (90) days.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="data-retention" names="data\ retention">
            <title>Data retention</title>
            <paragraph>Information entered into our bug tracker will be retained indefinitely
                and is typically made public. We will only use it to triage the
                problem.  Beyond that, we do not retain personally identifiable
                information about our users for longer than one week.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="data-security" names="data\ security">
            <title>Data security</title>
            <paragraph>We are committed to making sure your information is protected. We employ
                several physical and electronic safeguards to keep your information safe,
                including encrypted user passwords, two factor verification and authentication
                on passwords where possible, and securing connections with industry standard
                transport layer security. You are also welcome to contact us using GnuPG
                encrypted e-mail. Even with all these precautions, we cannot fully guarantee
                against the access, disclosure, alteration, or deletion of data through
                events, including but not limited to hardware or software failure or
                unauthorized use. Any information that you provide to us is done so entirely
                at your own risk.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="changes-and-updates-to-privacy-policy" names="changes\ and\ updates\ to\ privacy\ policy">
            <title>Changes and updates to privacy policy</title>
            <paragraph>We reserve the right to update and revise this privacy policy at any time. We
                occasionally review this Privacy Policy to make sure it complies with
                applicable laws and conforms to changes in our business. We may need to update
                this Privacy Policy, and we reserve the right to do so at any time. If we do
                revise this Privacy Policy, we will update the “Effective Date” at the top
                of this page so that you can tell if it has changed since your last visit. As
                we generally do not collect contact information and also do not track your
                visits, we will not be able to notify you directly. However, Anastasis clients
                may inform you about a change in the privacy policy once they detect that the
                policy has changed. Please review this Privacy Policy regularly to ensure that
                you are aware of its terms. Any use of our Services after an amendment to our
                Privacy Policy constitutes your acceptance to the revised or amended
                agreement.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="international-users-and-visitors" names="international\ users\ and\ visitors">
            <title>International users and visitors</title>
            <paragraph>Our Services are (currently) hosted in Germany. If you are a user
                accessing the Services from the Switzerland, Asia, US, or any other
                region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection,
                use, and disclosure that differ from the laws of Germany, please be
                advised that through your continued use of the Services, which is
                governed by the law of the country hosting the service, you are
                transferring your Personal Information to Germany and you consent to
                that transfer.</paragraph>
        </section>
        <section ids="questions" names="questions">
            <title>Questions</title>
            <paragraph>Please contact us at <reference refuri="mailto:privacy@anastasis.lu">privacy@anastasis.lu</reference> if you have questions about our
                privacy practices that are not addressed in this Privacy Statement.</paragraph>
        </section>
    </section>
</document>
